In my presentation
I’m going to introduce the subject
and then present the main points
and then elaborate on them
and then give examples, and then…
Wait. Why are you using “and then,” “and then” all the time?
I don’t know what else to say to move on to the next point
You can use “signpost language.”
What is “signpost language”?
Isn’t a signpost the signal along the road to direct the way?
Yes. So signpost language means the words and phrases
that guide the audience through the presentation
They indicate what has happened so far
and what is going to happen next
Do we use different signposts
throughout the whole presentation?
There is different signpost language for the introduction
the body and the conclusion.
Signposting can be effective
in keeping your audience focused
and knowing where you are in the presentation
What are some signpost phrases
I can use in the introduction?
Phrases like first of all
to begin with, let’s start by…
And I can use phrases like firstly, secondly
and lastly to indicate the order
Correct. And when moving on to the next point
you can say
I’ve talked about…, now let’s move on to…
How about elaborating and giving examples?
Is there anything else we can say
besides “in more detail” and “for instance”?
Sentence patterns like
“let me tell you more about…”
or “I’d like to expand on…”
can be used to paraphrase or for elaboration
I can also say “To illustrate this point…”
or “A good example of this is…” to give examples
Some key words we can use in the conclusion are
summarize, conclude and recap.
To invite questions, some useful phrases are
“Please feel free to ask questions”
and “I am happy to answer any questions.”
To put it simply, the audience won’t get “lost”
in the presentation when signpost language is used.
And I don’t have to repeat
“and then … and then … and then …” all the time.